Now! Listen, Kobato!
"Summer vacation" is our competition!
Our... competition?
That's right! Summer vacation means
beaches! Camping! Outdoor parties!
It is filled with all sorts of
distractions from hurt and pain.
Hey Dobato! Are you listening to me?!
A letter...
That is not a letter! It's a flyer! A flyer!
What did I tell you? Kompeito
collecting isn't going to be easy.
Watch out especially for summer festivals.
Summer Festival Notice
Sakura Park August 14, 15
Watch out especially for summer festivals.
Summer Festival Notice
Sakura Park August 14, 15
Flutes and drums, street vendors and yukata.
Summer Festival Notice
Sakura Park August 14, 15
They've even got folk dancing.
It's beautiful...
Now listen, Kobato!
I'm sure you already understand
what I'm trying to tell you!
I am not finished!
I won't let summer festivals get in the way.
I will heal everybody's broken hearts!
Kobato.
What should I do?
Even the most obvious of things
Are always such a challenge
I want to laugh when I'm happy
And sing whenever I want
Is all
They say my dreams will come true someday
But when will "someday" come?
I can't wait forever
On "1, 2, 3!" I'll spread open my arms
And let the light gather around me
Where is it?
Please tell me what I can do
I make the most of getting hurt
And run with all my might
Despite how many dozens of times I fall
And start crying
I surprise myself
In how much I believe in tomorrow
...Memories of Summer.
Summer festival...
Where could it have flown to?
Is this what you're looking for?
Yes, that's it!
Thank you very much!
Just a minute.
Here, use this.
Your hands are soaking wet.
Thank you very much.
What is she up to now?
It's a flyer for a summer festival.
It's already that season, is it?
Have you ever been to one?
Every summer, since I was a child.
Portable shrines, fairs... and the fireworks
are like blooming flowers lighting up.
Lit up?
But...
Maybe I won't be going this year.
Why not?
Hey! When we get to the pool, let's race!
Okay! I'm not going to lose to you!
Oh yeah? But you know what,
I can swim a little now.
Really?
I've got to get to my high school.
It's school day today.
Yomogi Kindergarten is on summer vacation!
Yukino.
Natsuki! Good morning.
You were walking with your eye on your
cell phone again, weren't you?
Better hurry, or you're going to be late.
Are you all right?
Kobato...
Ioryogi-san!
I feel heavy...
Are you okay?
No, I am not okay!
And you. You're losing to
summer festivals already.
Stay still. I'm going to help you get fired up!
Hang me out to dry.
That's the Seinan Women's
High School uniform.
Do you know Natsuki, Fujimoto?
No.
It's the high school attached to
Seinan Women's University.
It's where Ms. Sayaka and
Ms. Chitose graduated from.
You know everything.
It's a school for proper girls.
Not any place you would've been involved with.
He's mean again today too.
It's summer vacation at the kindergarten.
He's probably spending his entire
holiday working and studying.
By the way, it's dry. You're going
to return it, aren't you?
That's right!
Natsuki doesn't seem to be here.
Better hurry before the sun goes down.
There will be an official
announcement next term...
There she is!
There will be an official
announcement next term...
but the volunteer club led by Natsuki
Mizuhashi has been recognized
by the prefectural government for its
involvement in community beautification.
There will be an award.
So Natsuki's last name is Mizuhashi.
The one that wiped out is also in the same class.
And just because you're on vacation
doesn't mean you can stay up all night.
Oh, from this morning...
And just because you're on vacation
doesn't mean you can stay up all night.
Summer is an easy time to lose control.
Remember that you are students
of Seinan Women's High School.
Behave accordingly, and...
Yukino! You again?!
If you don't stop it, I'll have
to take that from you.
S-Sorry ma'am.
Well then, I'm now confirming the emergency
contact network for summer vacation.
Hey! Came out pretty good!
You've got talent.
You think so?
Have more confidence in yourself.
That's all.
Now, those of you in charge of cleaning
the pool, gather at the poolside.
She's coming.
Yes!
Excuse me!
Are you a student here?
No. I'm Kobato Hanato of Yomogi Kindergarten.
Kindergarten? What are you saying?
You over there. Hurry and get
someone from the office, will you?
Oh what a hassle. Kobato, run!
What? But why?
Just do as I say and run!
Okay, I'll try.
Where are you going?!
Anyway, I have to find Natsuki.
Hold on to the lens firmly.
Nothing beats the real thing.
You'll be able to afford one soon too, Yukino.
That girl was with Natsuki this morning.
Your name is Yukino?
Yeah.
I'm Kobato Hanato.
Natsuki.
This girl came looking for you.
Oh. From this morning.
I, Kobato Hanato, have come
to return your handkerchief!
You washed it for me?
Yes. But I don't own an iron.
I'm sorry for all the wrinkles.
Oh don't worry. Thank you very much.
W-Well then, I'm off.
What? But what about cleaning the pool?
Sorry Natsuki. I didn't tell you. I've got a job.
That's against school rules. You can't work.
I know... but...
Yukino!
Sorry we're late.
It's okay. Natsuki, I'm really sorry.
Yukino!
Yukino's working really hard
to buy her own camera.
We'll help clean the pool so let her go, okay?
I didn't know.
Um, Natsuki!
I-I'd like to join you!
Mizuhashi
Fujimoto was right.
This place really is out of my league.
But telling her you'd like to join her.
Is there a more direct pickup line?
Pickup line? Was it rude?
Sorry to keep you.
Um. Sorry for abruptly using
a line to pick you up!
I didn't feel like coming home by myself.
So I was happy.
I'm glad.
That photo...
It looks like Yukino.
That's when we were in elementary
school. A summer festival.
She's your best friend.
She was... I guess.
She isn't your best friend anymore?
Well because she avoids me.
Good morning, Natsuki!
Morning, Yukino. Hey your shirt's
sticking out at back.
What?!
Let me fix it for you.
We went to school together every day.
Sorry I'm late.
Look at your hair, Yukino!
Is it sticking out?! I'll be right back!
What!
Hurry back, Yukino!
And then, I don't know when, but...
Sorry Natsuki! I overslept! Go ahead without me!
Mhm. See you at school.
Then after we got into high
school, little by little...
And then you know what?
How beautiful...
Sorry, Natsuki. You go ahead.
R-Right.
Yukino.
If you're interested in photography,
why don't you join our club?
But I don't know if I can handle club activities.
Don't say that.
At least come and take a look.
Um, but...
Yeah, come visit us.
Now it's like, we're totally apart.
I don't even know what
Yukino's thinking anymore.
I'd like to help Natsuki.
How?
I don't know!
You don't know?!
Anyway, I'm going to go and talk with Yukino.
Thanks for your help.
I think we'll be ready in time
for the festival after all.
Yes.
Choose any one you like.
I'm sorry to bother you during work.
That's okay, I'm about finished
with this job anyway.
Is that right?
I've saved up enough money.
I can finally buy the camera I want when they
begin that sale at the station building tomorrow.
What about the one you had yesterday?
Yesterday?
Oh...
That belongs to a friend.
I really wanted my own though,
so I got a job and saved up.
That's very impressive, Yukino.
It's a hobby that began when I started taking
pictures with the camera on my mobile.
Now I'm totally involved.
I'm a lot closer to the photography club
members now. We have similar interests.
What about Natsuki?
Huh?
Don't you talk with her much?
I've been friends with Natsuki
since we were kids.
Matching phones.
Yeah.
Hey, let's go and get straps.
Let's get matching ones.
But if we have the same straps we
won't be able to tell which is which.
You're right.
I'm going to get this one!
Then I'm getting this one!
Watermelon 'cause my name means summer!
A snowman because my name means snow!
So cute!
Want to swap?
Sure!
I'll take good care of it!
I'll look after mine, too!
Don't you get along with Natsuki now?
Don't you like her anymore?
Of course I like her!
How could I ever dislike Natsuki?
She is my idol.
Oh come on, you're embarrassing me!
Let's take one together!
Okay!
Say cheese!
Let me take a proper one next time, okay?
After you improve your picture taking skills.
What?!
Natsuki and Yukino.
They really want to remain the best of friends.
Why aren't they able to do that?
I don't know. How should I know if
even they can't figure it out?
But... I wish there was something I could do.
Summer Sale
Yomogi Station
Excuse me. Where is the camera shop
that's having a sale today?
To get there...
Yes?
Hey. Let's try taking some pictures
as soon as we get back.
That's a great idea.
Natsuki...
Shopping?
Uh, yeah.
A single-lens reflex camera.
Oh.
Y-Yukino worked really hard to save
up and buy a great camera.
That's right.
The club members are all jealous.
Yeah, so Yukino why don't
you join our photo club?
Hey, good idea!
To celebrate your SLR camera debut!
I mean, you finally got that
camera you wanted so badly.
I know. Let's go to a photo
session sometime soon.
With your talent, Yukino, you'll
be sure to get good shots.
Yes, lets!
Right?
Right!
This is ridiculous!
I mean, photos can look pretty good just by
copying the composition used in ads.
Too many people mistake that with talent.
And that includes you, Yukino.
I hate amateurs who think they're professional
when they don't even have what it takes.
Yukino!
Natsuki!
Yukino.
Sure, I wish I had talent.
But right now I just enjoy taking pictures.
I love photography. That's all.
Um... well... I'm happy for you that you were
able to buy that camera you like. Oh and...
I'm sorry.
Would you let me be alone?
Why did I say that?
It's gone. The strap is gone. Why?
It's nowhere...
Hey, where are you going now?
That wasn't right for Natsuki to act the way she
did! I must go and have a word with her!
And tell her what?
Well, um... Anyway, I can't just
leave things like this!
What's wrong?
It's gone! My mobile strap! It's gone!
I'll help you look for it!
I've looked there. I've looked everywhere.
Over and over. It's gone!
What am I going to do? It's because of all those
horrible things I said to Yukino, I know it.
Anyway, I'll help you find it!
What am I going to do?
What am I? What am I?
Natsuki...
I found it.
Thank you!
Thank you, Kobato!
You and Yukino. You're still
best friends, aren't you?
Maybe I was intimidated by Yukino a bit.
Could that have been because she was so
beautiful working hard at what she likes?
Yukino has always been a bit different.
Sometimes I'd look at her as
someone far out of my reach.
I felt like she would leave me
behind. That scared me.
That's why I had to work harder
with my studies and stuff.
But I was the one that first pushed
Yukino away from me.
Natsuki, may I borrow your phone?
1 new email message
Natsuki
Natsuki...
1 new email message
Natsuki
Re: I'm sorry.
1 attached file
Retrieving
Natsumi... You've still got the strap.
Yukino!
Yukino. I'm so sorry about
what I said earlier. I uh...
I have mine too.
I've kept mine all this time, too.
Yukino...
I've kept mine, too.
Ms. Sayaka and Ms. Chitose,
have you ever quarreled?
What?
I can't even begin to count the
number of times we quarreled.
Oh? Is that so?
Just think of all the times we didn't
speak to each other for a while.
I guess you're right. There were such times.
But you are best friends.
Natsuki, smile!
Oh come on, you're embarrassing me.
Wow!
The fireworks are beautiful.
Okay, today, ninety points! Go ahead, take it!
The fireworks. They're beautiful, aren't they?
What's this?! You're letting the
summer festival comfort you?!
That's not right. Negative two hundred
points for you, Dobato!
The fireworks are beautiful, don't you think?
Hey! Did you hear what I said?!
They're beautiful.
Everyone dreams of flying
But they let gravity trick them
Honestly, everyone is already able to fly
I bet the reason that child looks so terribly sad
Is because he
Accidentally lost his shadow somewhere
In that case
If I could just tell you, "Thank you,"
And you laugh and reply, "Thank you"
That exchange would fill you with joy
It would make you feel so happy
There's nothing to worry about
Since we're together
It's strange how I'm crying
Even though I'm happy
Next episode
...The Boy's Organ Days.
Even though I'm happy
Next episode
...The Boy's Organ Days.